Hi, I'm Dean, and this is The MongoDB Podcast.
你好   我是 Dean   这里是 MongoDB 播客
Today we're going to be talking about a game I made called "osu!".
今天我们来聊聊我创造的一款叫 osu! 的游戏
Welcome to The MongoDB Podcast.
欢迎来到 MongoDB 播客
And as ever, thanks for joining us for another episode.
和往常一样   感谢您加入我们新的一集专访
My name is Shane McAllister,
我的名字叫 Shane McAllister
and if it's not too late, happy new year to all our listeners.
如果现在不算太迟的话   祝各位新年快乐哦
And we're very much looking forward to SUPERB 2023,
另外   我们非常期待今年的超级碗比赛
and some exciting episodes to bring your way.
而且我们还会带来一些激动人心的专访
So as ever, please remember to hit that subscribe button...
还是那句话   无论你用的是哪个播客软件
on whatever podcast pot from you use,
都请点击“订阅”按钮   关注我们
so you don't miss a thing.
这样你就不会错过我们了
On this week's episode, we dive into the area of gaming,
在这一周的专访中   我们要深入游戏领域
and more particularly, beat matching and rhythm games.
*本视频不会译作“音游”“音乐游戏”而是“节奏游戏”，因为显然后者是前者的子集，前者还包括“旋律游戏”甚至“音量游戏”，比如《
不要停！八分音符酱♪》。
尤其是节奏游戏*
And I'm delighted to be joined by Dean Herbert, founder of osu!.
今天很高兴邀请到 Dean Herbert   osu! 的创造者
osu! is a hugely popular online rhythm game.
osu! 是个倍受欢迎的在线节奏游戏
It's open source and uses the Realm .NET SDK from MongoDB.
*新版的 lazer 客户端。
它是开源软件*   用到了 MongoDB 的 Realm .NET SDK
And in this episode, we learn more about its inception, why Dean built it,
本期访谈中   我们要了解它的开端   为什么 Dean 创造了它
and how it's grown hugely in the many years since Dean single handily built it himself,
自从 Dean 单枪匹马地创造它以来   它是怎样在多年间取得巨大发展的
and how he's turned his hobby into his day job,
以及他是怎么把这项爱好变成全职职业的
and built a huge and loyal community following.
他是怎么建立起一个庞大而忠诚的追随者社区的
Let's jump right in.
让我们开始吧
On the show, today, we are joined by Dean.
今天   在这里   我们邀请到了 Dean
Dean, please introduce yourself to the audience here in the MongoDB Podcast.
Dean   请你对 MongoDB 播客的观众做个自我介绍
Tell us who you are and what do you do.
告诉我们你是谁   你干的是什么
Yep, hi, I'm Dean. I made a game called osu!.
嗨   我是 Dean   我创造了一个叫 osu! 的游戏
Been working on it since 2007. So it's been kind of my life for the last 15 years.
自 2007 年来我就一直致力于此   所以在过去十五年间它成了我的一种生活方式
Started off as a bit of a hobby thing, um,
我从一个爱好做起
I got into it because I was always interested in the rhythm game, and such things.
我就无法自拔   因为我总是对节奏游戏和诸如此类的事情感兴趣
In my childhood, I grew up in Australia.
我在澳大利亚长大   度过童年
and we had arcades, which occasionally got these rhythm games in.
那会儿我们还有开这种节奏游戏的机厅
And I was always into music and gaming, so that combination really struck something with me.
我一直喜欢音乐和游戏   所以这种组合真的打动了我
But we didn't have that many arcades,
但是那种机厅并不多
and quite often they would shut down, all these games would just disappear, out of the blue.
而且没过多久它们就会关闭   所有这些游戏都会突然消失
So when the Internet came around and,
于是   当互联网出现时
these people were making online simulators of these rhythm games,
有的人就做了这类节奏游戏的在线模拟器
and suddenly I had access to play the games whenever I wanted on my PC.
突然间   我就又能在电脑上玩到它们   想玩啥就玩啥了
So that's kind of how this is born out of that.
这就是 osu! 诞生的背景
So take us back to the beginning.
那我们就回到开头的话题
Ask there's a Japanese meaning behind the name? And also...
osu! 是有个日语含义对吧   另外
for our audience who are quite wide and varied,
我们的听众是相当广泛和多样的
who mightn't understand rhythm and beat matching games,
有的听众可能并不了解什么是“节奏游戏”
can you explain a little bit about where they originated from,
你能解释一下这些游戏的起源
and what's involved in playing those?
玩这些会涉及什么
Yeah, sure thing.
好的
So there's a lot of different styles of rhythm games,
节奏游戏有很多风格
but osu! is based on,
而 osu! 是基于
it's actually based on a game which was published by an Nintendo on the Nintendo DS,
是基于一款发布在 NDS 上的游戏
and that game is called 'Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan'.
叫做《押忍！战斗！应援团》
and it was kind of a story driven game where,
这是一款故事驱动的游戏
you would play through this journey with cheerleaders,
游戏中   你会和啦啦队队员一起
they are actually male cheerleaders called the ouendan.
这些队员都是男的   叫做“应援团”
And the word 'osu!' in that is kind of part of their chant which,
而“osu!”(押忍！)是他们的一个口号
which they're like trying to encourage people that,
他们想鼓励那些
have these stories in life where they've, you know, hit at the rock bottom.
那些经历过人生低谷的人
And you have to play along to the game in time with the music,
你得随着音乐玩这款游戏
tapping on the Nintendo DS screen to get them into a better state of mind,
在 NDS 屏幕上点击   让他们情绪高涨
and quite often save the day.
最后拨云见日   屡战屡胜
So It was born out of that. I played that game.
这就是 osu! 的起源   我玩了那款游戏
And obviously, because it was published to a mobile system,
但显然   因为它是面向一个小游戏机系统发布的
you are limited to play the levels that were included in the game, and,
你只能玩到游戏自带的歌
I immediately wanted to add my own songs into the game,
我就马上想要往里面加自己选的歌
you know, to create new levels for it.
相当于创建新关卡
So that's, that's how osu! was born.
于是 osu! 就诞生了
Okay, so it's, it's 15 years ago since this inception.
那么   自从你开始   已经十五年了
What size is it now? What sizes the team?
现在它规模有多大   它的团队有多大
and what's your day to day role in the team?
以及你在团队中的日常角色是什么
Maybe for the first five or even more years, it was just me working on the game.
在头五年   好像还多几年   是只有我在维护这个游戏的
Started off as a hobby, and I eventually I was,
开始是作为一个爱好   最后就（辞职开发游戏了）
I originally was employed full time as a .NET developer.
我原来是全职 .NET 程序员
I was working on migrating some J2EE systems across the .NET. So,
当时我做的是把 J2EE 系统迁移到 .NET
yeah, I had a good experience, with a good amount of experience with .NET.
所以我有丰富的 .NET 开发经验
Yeah, over the years, it was originally just me and I kind of,
是的   最初只由我业余搞搞
moved from the game being a side project of being full time.
这些年来   人们对这个游戏越来越感兴趣
As people started to show more interest in the game and actually,
然后他们真的投入金钱贡献
financially contribute to it.
于是我就全职开发游戏了
That's fascinating, because I think in my own past,
很了不起   因为在我的过去
I've met a lot of developers who are frustrated game developers,
我遇到过许多失意的游戏开发者
you know, so they go down the road,
他们也走在（游戏开发之）路
exactly what you're describing, Dean, which is, you know, following their passion,
就和你的描述一样    追寻他们的激情
following something that they're interested in. But,
追随他们感兴趣的东西
it's, it's really, really hard to turn that into the day job,
然而   把它作为全职工作真的很不容易
but you've managed that.
但你做到了
Yeah, I guess, um, a certain degree of luck there.
嗯   或许我有运气成分在里面
And just I had a huge amount of passion towards the game,
我就是对这游戏有极大的热情
so I was spending every waking hours.
于是我醒着的每一刻都投入其中
Oftentimes I was sleeping like 3 hours a day for like, years at a time.
很多时候   我每天只睡三个小时   这样一干就是好几年
Back when I was of a younger age, I constantly went on this game,
当我年轻的时候   我一直在做这个游戏
so people saw the amount of change I was putting into it,
大家看到了   因为我的投入   这个游戏变化之大
and the amount I was listening to users' feedback,
（大家也看到）我倾听用户反馈的次数之多
I guess, and giving them exactly what they asked for.
然后我就满足他们要求的东西
Yet, in the early days, I made some very rapid development progress,
早年间   我取得了一些非常快速的开发进展
maybe at the detriment of code quality.
也许代价就是代码质量很差
But, yeah, over the years, we have increased the size of the teams.
但是   这些年里   我们扩大了团队规模
I think there's about eight of us full time working on the game now,
现在一共有八人在全职开发 osu! 了
various elements of the game, the client and the infrastructure behind it.
包括游戏的各种元素   客户端及其背后的基础设施
And then we also have a huge amount of community contributions, so,
而且我们还有大量的社区贡献
basically volunteers that keep the user content,
基本上   是志愿者在保持内容的产出
the curation systems of the game, running the moderation of the online community.
游戏的策划系统   运行在线社区的管理
And so you're based in Japan. Where are the rest of the team?
你居住在日本   团队中的其他人在哪里
Are they in Japan as well too? Are they spread globally?
他们也在日本么   还是说你们遍布世界各处
Yes, so we do have a few devs over in Japan,
是的   我们确实有几个开发者在日本
but most of the team is working remotely.
但大多数成员是远程工作的
We ve always, um,
其实我们一直
basically promoted people up from these volunteer roles into kind of full time roles,
基本上把人们从志愿者角色提升到全职角色
and they've just been working from wherever they are in the world.
他们一直在他们那里工作
So we have a few in America, some in Australia,
所以有几个在美国   有几个在澳大利亚
some in East Asia as well, different areas.
还有些在东亚   反正是遍布全球
Wow, that's excellent. So obviously there,
那很精彩诶   那么
you mentioned the inception was from the game that you saw, an Nintendo game.
你提到最初这个游戏是基于一款 NDS 游戏
There's obviously other kind of rhythm matching, beat matching games out there.
显然   世界上还有其他类型的节奏游戏
What sets osu! apart from those?
是什么使 osu! 与所有这些都与众不同
I guess the main thing is that we've always been very community driven,
我想主要是因为我们的动力大部分来自社区
focused on user content. So from day one,
我们致力于用户内容   所以 osu! 从第一天起
the game kind of shipped with an editor...
就自带一个编辑器
where you could create these levels in the game.
你可以在那里创建游戏关卡
The game never came with levels included.
*原文如此，但事实上，安装好的游戏一直都会自带十余个谱面，且自带谱面会不定期更换。Dean 的意思应该是，osu! 没有“官方谱面”，哪怕是自带谱面也都是由普通玩家制作的。关于自带谱面的决定流程，请看评论区置顶。
osu! 从来不自带关卡*
It's always up to the user to create that content.
要制作什么完全取决于用户
Yeah. And the other thing is, uh,
还有一件事情是
I guess I've always tried to run the game very differently...
我们一直在尝试着以一种
to how the industry is progressing.
与游戏工业有天差地别的方式来运营游戏
I'm not a huge fan of the, um, the monetization of gaming these days, so,
我并不喜欢当今把游戏给货币化的方式
so I've always done things the way I would want them to be done if I was a user of the game,
所以我总是以玩家想要的方式去运营
has never been about getting profit from the game.
从未想过在游戏中获利
Okay, so you're taking it from that perspective.
于是你就从那样的角度对待了
So I think, you know, certainly it brings us to the question of revenue.
所以这当然会让我们想到收入的问题
And I know, and I've been browsing the osu! site,
我浏览了 osu! 网站
you've got an amazing swag store. I love the plushes.
*去年年末出的限量版抱枕，现已售罄。
你们有家很棒的装饰品商店   尤其是那个抱枕*   我挺喜欢
And obviously there's and silary revenue there.
很明显   那里有很多收入
But how does osu! supported? How is your team of eight developers supported?
但是 osu! 是怎么坚持的呢   你们八个人靠什么吃饭
Yeah, so we do have the merchandise side of things,
是的   所以我们确实有商品方面的东西
but that doesn't really um that.
但那点钱算是（杯水车薪）
That only covers basically the tournament prizes side of things.
那点收入只能涵盖比赛奖金之类的东西
These days, most of our revenue comes from people just donating to the game.
现在   我们的大多数收入来自玩家的直接捐赠
We have this system called Supporter Tags,
我们有一套系统叫“支持者标签”
which is basically the ability to buy or donate, contribute for x months or x years.
玩家买个几月几年的支持者标签
And you get a few in-game perks,
我们就给予他们一些游戏内的额外功能
things like more customization for your profile,
比如   自定义个人主页
and just a few features inside the game that make it more...
还有一些游戏内部的
easy to access certain features of the game,
更便利的功能
ability to operate more content than normally uses. Just a few perks like that.
与一般玩家相比能支配的东西更多   就像这样的几个功能
I've always tried to keep the perks that you get ...
我一直把这些特权放在
limited to things which actually cost us more.
花费我们更多精力的地方
So there's actually a tangible mapping...
于是这之间有了实在的关系
of the many people paying to what they get in return.
即   你出钱   就有相应回报
That's very interesting. And I suppose, I mean,
挺有趣的   另外
we are used to the larger gaming sphere,
我想我们已经习惯了更大的游戏领域
where that is not always the most altruistic intentions there.
但那些游戏的赚钱心可能更强
it's profit and large as and building bigger and bigger games and bigger developer teams...
它的利润很大   但游戏规模也会越大   开发团队也越大
at bigger cost, etc. as well too. And I will get later on, hopefully, into the community,
成本等等也越大   接着我们来谈谈游戏社区
because that is super impressive, what you are doing your community.
你运营的社区实在让人印象深刻
But just again, to fill in the background, you mentioned that,
但是我们还得补充下背景   比如你刚才提到
you know, you launched it, it didn't come with any beatmaps there.
你创立 osu! 时   并没有现成的谱面
You had to create them yourself. How does that happen?
你只能自己做   这是怎么回事
What is a beatmap? How are they made?
什么是“谱面”   谱面是怎么做的
And how many have people created over the time that you've run osu!?
这十多年来   玩家们一共做了多少谱面
Yes, so that's the other thing.
啊   那是另外一回事了
When I first made the game, there were other simulators on the PC platform but,
我第一次完成这个游戏时   电脑平台上已经有些这个游戏的模拟器了
they didn't really come with the tools that let you jump straight into to creating the level. So,
但它们都没有能让你能够直接创作关卡的工具
So I basically from the main menu of the game, you can go into the editor and then use...
而   自 osu! 的主菜单中   你就可以进入编辑器
Drag any MP3 you want to create a level for,
拖进一个你想做关卡的 MP3
and set up the timing, so you tap in time to the to the song to get the BPM set up,
对好节奏   敲鼓点来把 BPM 设置好
and then you can just start placing objects on the screen.
而后你就可以在屏幕上开始布置物件了
So we have three different kinds of objects.
我们有三种物件
There's like Standard Hits, and then Hold Hits, which run over duration,
一是圆圈   二是滑条   会持续一段时间
and then Spin as, which is a kind of gimmick,
三是转盘   一种小把戏
where you have to spin as fast as you can.
你要以最快的速度转动
So it gives you a lot of flexibility over what you want,
所以它给了你很大的灵活性
how you want to create the level for the song.
每首歌你都能随心所欲地制作关卡
The other aspect is that...
另一方面
when you place these objects, you can give them special sounds.
你在放置物件时   可以赋予它们特殊的声音
So you can actually create, like almost a drum rhythm over the original song,
所以你实际上可以在原始歌曲上创建一个鼓点节奏
which gives it a new character.
给予它新的特征
And this is one of the main reasons I actually was very interested in this game,
这就是我对这个游戏感兴趣的原因之一
more so than other rhythm games, is that Nintendo,
比起其他节奏游戏来说    任天堂的这款
or INIS, which is the original publisher, they created these...
应该是 INIS   他们才是原开发者   他们在原曲之上
all my soundscapes on top of the original songs,
创造了新的声音景观
and they just stuck in my head.
他们存留在我的脑海中
Every time I heard a song on the radio, I could hear these.
每次我在电台里听到一首歌   我就能听到这些节奏
I wanted to add these rhythms on top of the song.
我就想在原曲上加入这些节奏
Okay, so when you're uploading an MP3, is that any MP3,
所以如果你要上传一个 MP3    是任意的 MP3 都能用吗
or is there a copyright reason, issues, etc. As well, too, I would imagine.
还是说   这本身就存在版权问题   我能想象得到
So it's it's all local when you'd actually drag the MP3 in,
你把 MP3 拖进来时    一切操作都在本地
so you can, in theory, had anything.
所以   理论上讲   你可以做任何事情
And, oh, I see, so you can...
那就是说   你也可以
so you're creating the beatmap on top of a popular piece of music,
用热门曲目来制谱
but yes, your local piece of music.
但它存储在本地
But we do allow that to be upload to the service.
但是我们是允许把它们上传到服务器的
So I guess it was a very great area for a long period of time...
所以   很长一段时间里
where people were uploading this content.
这都是用户创作的天堂
We obviously take it down whenever we get requests.
当然   如果收到（下架）请求   我们肯定会下架
But the other thing that was really good is once we...
但有件好事是
over the last five or six years, and we actually started turning in a good profit,
最近这五六年   我们有了可观的盈利
I've contributed to all that profit back to licensing the music.
我们把这些收入都投入到音乐版权中
So we've gone back retroactively,
我们已经追溯到了过去那些
and all the most popular levels that have been uploaded to the game.
谱面库里最受欢迎的谱面
We've reached out to the artists, and we've got something like 4000 license tracks now,
我们会联系那些艺术家   现在我们已经买下了约四千首歌的版权
which I think is the most of any rhythm game out there. So we've,
好像是所有节奏游戏中最多的吧
So we've tried our best to bring that back around, into the legal realm.
我们已经尽力把它们带回来   能合法地使用
I love this story. This is great. And overall,
我喜欢这个故事   挺不错的
how many tracks have been uploaded to osu!?
那么    osu! 谱面库到现在一共有多少谱面呢
Yeah, there's, there's something over 2 million, I think, levels have been created.
嗯   超过两百万
And then of that, we have, like a process which...
此外   我们还有一套机制
ensures that some of the levels are very high quality,
来保证谱面的质量
and they get what we call the ranked status, which, uh,
*“Ranked”谱面，通常译作“上架”谱面，是经过至少七名玩家（五名普通玩家和两位谱面审核成员）认可的谱面。请参见 osu! wiki 的相关章节。
叫做“上架状态”*
gives them leaderboards. And...
上架的谱面会开放排行榜
if you have the special features,
还会有一些特殊特性
and I think we have something like 50000 of those.
目前上架谱面大约有五万个吧
Wow. So speaking of numbers in that scale,
哇   所以说   在这个规模的谱面库上
what size is the osu! community?
osu! 社区又有多大
How many players do you have?
玩家共有多少
What sort of countries are they in? How often do they play?
他们在哪些国家   他们多长时间玩一次
Sure, yes. So we um,
好的   那么
we've got something like 30 million registered users now.
我们的注册用户大约有三千万
The concurrent user base is something...
在高峰期   同时在线人数
in the range of 20 to 40 thousand during the peak.
在两万到四万之间
Over the last few years, we had huge influx of users during COVID,
疫情这几年有大量的用户涌入
that got us up to something like 48000 concurrent users at peak.
现在的同时在线人数能跑到四万八了
We see people playing, like every month, about two to three million people come back.
月活也不少   每个月大约有两到三百万人回来
So that's the ongoing user base, I guess, is around two, two mill.
因此   这就是持续的用户群   大约是两百万
Wow. This is amazing, Dean. I mean,
这太令人惊叹了   Dean   我觉得
obviously I've spoken with you before, and we've interacted over a while,
我以前和你谈过   我们已经互动了一段时间
but I did not know this stats with this large.
但我不知道统计数据会有这么大
That is, they are sort of numbers that most...
其他大多数游戏公司看到你们的数据
game companies and businesses alone would kill for.
肯定恨不得宰了你们
That is incredible that you built this from...
不可思议的是   你只身建立起游戏
the inception yourself and then threw into the small team.
最后运营到一个小团队
And more important, the style and the nature with which you've been building this.
尤其是   你构建它的风格和性质令人惊叹
And I know you said earlier, community is really big to osu!,
你之前说到   社区对 osu! 发展很重要
and you have, you've contests and tournaments and live streams.
osu! 有比赛    锦标赛和直播
Tell us a little bit about those.
请谈谈这几个东西吧
Yeah. So all our tournaments are basically community run.
那么   我们的锦标赛基本都是社区运营
We do have an official one, which is called the osu! World Cup,
我们也有一个官方的比赛   叫 osu! 世界杯
Very topical for the moment, anyway.
挺应景的   放在这里
That is, like, it's financially supported by us,
osu! 世界杯由官方提供资金
but it's still run heavily by the community.
但还是极大程度地依靠社区运转
And yeah, we have various contests going on,
此外还有各种比赛
so things like fan art contests and composition contests for songs to be used in the game,
比如   同人绘画比赛   编曲比赛
and also for the levels, obviously,
当然   还有谱面的比赛
as we do a lot of ongoing things like that,
我们做了很多这样的持续的事情
just to invigorate the community, I guess.
都是为了振兴社区吧   我想
Yeah. So you have, as you said, you know,
对   正如你所说
you run into 30 million registered, you know,
你有三千万注册用户
tens of thousands, kind of concurrently, etc. as well.
数万人同时在线   等等
We talk a little bit about the tech stack in a while.
我们待会会聊聊技术栈
but where is your most popular country?
但还有个问题   哪些国家的玩家最活跃
What's, you know, going back to the beatmaps,
还有   关于谱面
is there a very popular style of beatmap?
谱面所用的曲子中   有没有一类最受欢迎的歌
Or do they go in and out of vogue?
还是说   它们会时而流行   时而过时
Yes. So, uh, the top countries, I guess, is the US and Russia.
嗯   最热门的国家   大概是美国和俄罗斯
So we have had a bit of drop off in financial support on...
*似乎是指 osu! 的推广，但这与 osu! 公开的运作模式相悖。此外“world event”指的是什么也不很明确。欢迎大家讨论 peppy 想表达的是什么意思。
由于疫情爆发   最近一两年
one of those two over the last year or so, went due to world events.
我们减少了对其中一个国家的资金投入*
But yeah, over the years, that has changed.
但是   以前的 osu! 可不是这样
So we used to have a huge Asian following. But,
以前我们有大量的亚洲玩家
but it seems like certain countries come in and go out,
但是这些国家的玩家时而来时而去
and the style of music we see, or beat maps, it really does vary.
还有   用来制谱的音乐类型相当多样
We have basically every genre you could think of,
你能想到什么流派   我们都有这类谱面
but the most popular levels in the game are the ones which...
但最受欢迎的谱面
seem to give higher score than they should.
*中文社区俗称 pp 图。
是那种看起来会送分的谱面*
so people are willing to get to, yeah, to get the highest score in levels.
大家都会去一次次地赌   尝试拿下榜首
So there's one which is 30s long,
*举两例：Harumachi Clover  编号：842412；Make a Move  编号：765778
有一首歌只有三十秒长*
that people are constantly retrying to get the highest score,
玩家一直在尝试得到最高分
and that's, that's one of our most popular.
那是我们最火的谱面之一
So they're doing that to basically level up.
所以他们这样做基本上是为了升级（刷 pp）
And it's pretty much you have to keep it.
而且你的成绩还得经得考验
Yes, yeah, it's all about increasing a statistics.
这都是在往上刷统计数据
And when I looked at... you have a great table on the website...
我看到 osu! 网站上有一张很棒的表格
for rankings and country rankings and player ranking.
对国家和玩家进行排名
And, you know, when you go into the users,
我点进用户页发现
I see users play counts of into the hundreds of thousands.
他们都有成百上千次游玩记录
So is that cumulatively over the years?
这是年复一年累计的吗
It is, yeah.
是的
Do they do anything else?
它们还干别的事吗
It would see if you had things in a hundred hundreds of thousands, for example.
就是说   你把时间都用在一遍遍重复这个事情上了
One of the most impressive things to me is there's actually people that...
让我印象最深的一件事是
stream this game full time these days,
现在真的有玩家全天直播 osu! 了
and they're making a living of that...
他们就以此为生
they're supporting their own production teams of a game that I made.
他们正在支持我制作的游戏的制作团队
and that just kind of blows my mind.
这让我很震惊
In some cases, I think they're actually making more than the game itself.
在某些情况下   我认为他们实际上比游戏（官方）还赚更多
That's an interesting one.
挺有趣的
That is, yeah, I mean, we see the rise of that,
也就是说   我们看到了它的崛起
certainly over the last number of years, and again, particularly during COVID when,
在过去的几年里   尤其是在疫情期间
people are at home and, you know,
人们都呆在家里
you've multi screens as well,
你（和大家一样）手里不止一个屏幕
so I think a lot of people stream in the background while they're,
很多人都在家里开直播
Um, Yeah.
是的
That's incredible. That's a great community. Yeah, most definitely.
这真是不可思议   伟大的社区   的确
This is, you know, sounds really interesting.
这个游戏听起来很有趣
If I want to get started with osu!, what do I do? Where do I go?
如果我想要入坑 osu!   我应该做什么
How do I get playing?
我要怎么玩到它
Yep. So you can grab the game off our website: osu.ppy.sh
好的   你可以从我们的官网下载   osu.ppy.sh
Or if you want to try out the new version,
或者   如果你想尝试新版本
which we've currently been basically rewriting the game from the ground up,
也就是我们全新重写的版本
and that's on GitHub right now. That's the open source, part of it.
*例如，根据官方开发博客，反作弊部分会被抽离出来，单独开发，不予开源。
它就在 GitHub 上   而且是开源的   部分是*
Go to @ppy on GitHub, I'm sure you'll find it pretty easily.
去 GitHub 上找到 @ppy   相信你很容易找到
And yet, all the account registration, everything's done from the game itself.
账户注册都在客户端内部实现了
So this is it.
就是这样
Great, and I see that, I loved. I went into the rules section.
很好   我明白了   接着我们聊聊社区规则
Your community rules are very fair, very equitable.
你们的社区规则是非常公平公正的
But the first one is that you have one account, and one account only for life.
但第一大规定就是   一人一号   终身不许开小号
Can you explain to me a little bit about that decision why you went down that and,
你能给我解释一下这个决定吗   为什么你这么做
and purely to stop gamification?
还有为什么要纯粹地停止游戏化
Basically, it's to ensure the integrity of the leaderboards.
基本上是为了确保排行榜的完整性
If people were allowed to create as many accounts as they want,
如果让玩家随心所欲地创建账号
you would see people like showing up at like, rank one, rank two, rank three.
就会出现榜一榜二榜三都是同一人的奇观
So that's the main reason.
这是主要原因
It's kind of just stuck that way over the years.
多年来   这规定就这样坚持了下来
It's one of the harder rules to enforce, as you can imagine.
这是最难执行的规则之一   你可以想象得到
I can imagine. Yes, how do you please that?
我能想象   那你怎么能检测到呢
We have various metrics are similar to, I guess,
我们会看多重指标
what advertising companies do to track people online.
这些指标和广告公司的在线追踪程序类似
We do our best, but also,
我们尽力了   但是
we generally don't enforce that rule unless we need to,
除非有必要   否则我们一般不会死撑这一规则
unless we see people actually be abusing the system to a greater extent.
除非我们看到人们实际上在更大程度上滥用该系统
So like my thinking is, is always that,
我的想法一直都是
if people aren't causing detrimental experience to other users,
如果人们没有对其他玩家造成有害的体验
if they're not affecting the general user experience, then I don't really,
如果他们没有影响到全体用户的体验
put too much effort into tracking them down.
那么我真的不会花太多精力去追踪他们
So we know where to go, we know where to get it.
也就是说   我们清楚我们的目标   和怎样实现目标
Obviously, if you're only getting it now,
显然   如果你现在才开始玩
you have a lot of ground to make up with all of the other players and everything else.
你有很多地方需要与所有其他玩家和东西一起弥补
But, the other thing is that it's a very casual game,
你别慌啊   其实它是一个非常休闲的游戏
so you can just jump in, play once and, you know, never come back, or,
你可以下载后只玩一次   然后弃坑
you know, play it very casually.
或者非常随意的玩
It's not one of the games where you have to be competitive...
这不是那种你必须保持竞争力
or keep up with the ongoing systems.
亦或是要跟上正在进行的系统的游戏之一
OK, so you can dip in and out,
好的   也就是说   你可以自由进入或者退出
as time permits, and, you know, as...
只要时间允许   想怎么玩都行
Yeah, you don't have to put several hundred thousand hours into the game...
是的   你不需要在 osu! 中投入成百上千小时
or whatever people are doing.
也不需要和其他玩家一样氪金氪周边之类
Very good, very good.
非常好
So talk to me a little bit.
让我们接着下一个话题
Let's get deeper into the technology behind, Dean.
我们来聊聊这背后的技术   Dean
Sure.
好的
Like, with that sort of numbers, with that large amount of registrations,
既然你有如此之多的注册用户
that amount of current users,
如此之多的同时在线人数
I'm really keen to understand a little bit more about how you built it,
我真的很想更多地了解你是如何构建它的
and what are the core technologies behind it?
它背后的核心技术是什么
Yeah, so, um, it's, it's actually an interesting one,
那将会非常有趣
because I did a talk recently on the infrastructure,
因为我最近做了一个关于基础设施的讲座
and I got a lot of feedback from people being very impressed with how,
我就收到了听众反馈   他们对我们在
um, how lane our team is on our infrastructure for the size of the game.
基础设施方面的表现印象相当深刻
And that's something I've always aimed for is, uh,
这是我一直以来的目标
to keep things as simple as possible, because,
就是让事情尽可能简单
I've been basically single handling, running the infrastructure for the game,
我基本上是孤军作战   独自运行游戏的基础设施
even to this date.
到今天也不例外
I do have one other person helping me with, um,
我确实有一个人帮我
some migration we are doing to Kubernetes these days,
在这几年帮我迁移到 Kubernetes
kind of containerize everything.
帮我做容器化的各种工作
But we our infrastructure these days, it's changed over the years, obviously.
显然   我们的基础设施在这几年有了变化
as we've had to scale up to more users.
这是为了要扩大用户群
But we are using, um, DigitalOcean as our main host for cloud hosting.
当前   我们选择 DigitalOcean 作为我们的云主机主要提供商
We run something like 150 different Droplets doing different stuff on there.
我们买了 150 个不同的 Droplet 单元   用来干不同的事情
And then we also use S3 for storage
我们也用 S3 做存储
and OVH for some of the higher bandwidth distribution.
和 OVHcloud 公司的一些高带宽分布系统
I wonder things is we don't rely on Steam or any other distribution platforms,
我们不依赖 Steam 或其他分发平台   这点我自己都惊讶
so we kind of have to bear that ourselves, all the updating infrastructure,
所以我们不得不自己承担所有基础设施的更新
everything is kind of ridden from the ground up.
一切都是从头开始的
That's one of the things that really interests me, so I enjoy doing that,
这一点很激起我的兴趣   所以我喜欢做这事
keeping it all completely independent of these other systems.
保持这一切完全独立于这些其他系统
Sure. And in the time that you've been doing it, then, Dean, what has changed?
是的   另外   你做 osu! 的这些年   有哪些事情是改变了的   Dean
Obviously, you know, you mentioned DigitalOcean and S3, etc.
显然   你提到 DigitalOcean 和 S3 等等
But if you've been building this initially, starting yourself 15 years ago,
但如果拉长目光   从你开始开发的十五年看
you've seen a huge amount of changes in the tech landscape.
你已经看到了技术领域的巨大变化
And then how, you know, where did you start?
那么   你的起点在哪里
How did you manage the changes over time,
你是怎么一路下来接受这些变化
the migrations that you needed to do, etc.?
完成所需要的迁移   等等
Yep. So, um,
好的   那么
I did originally start was just running on my home server, basically,
最初我是直接在我家里的服务器上运行的
back in the late 2000, 2008, 2009,
在 00 年代末   2008 年   2009 年
and then gradually scaled up from there,
从那里逐渐拓展
so went to share hosting, then dedicated service, then more dedicated service.
于是去买了共享主机   然后是专用服务   然后是更专用的服务
Then at some point got a bit annoyed at switching between hosting platforms,
然后在某一天对在托管平台之间切换感到有点恼火
um, because I had to basically rent out servers.
嗯   那会儿我们还得租服务器
It was very hard to get a good level of remote support from these hosting companies.
你很难从那种小公司得到很好的远程支持
So when DigitalOcean came around, it was very enticing,
所以当 DigitalOcean 出现时   它非常诱人
you know, virtualizing this and making it a lot...
它把这些都虚拟化
easier to migrate between different servers.
使得在不同服务器之间迁移变得容易得多
And also they had a very good support,
而且他们的支持也很不错
to a level that I had never experienced before.
其服务水平是我以前从未经历过的好
We've, we... our database is MySQL,
osu! 的（服务器）数据库是 MySQL
and we've had to scale that up over the years.
十几年来   我们要拓展这些数据库
We used to have just a single database,
以前我们只有一个数据库
but these days it's something like 5 different service running in a small cluster.
但是现在它是一个小集群中运行的五个不同的服务
And, yeah, just constant scaling, I guess.
就这样不断拓展
Excellent. Excellent. And why we're on that subject.
真棒   下一个话题
Let's talk a little bit about why, uh, I came to meet you a year or two ago.
我们来谈谈一两年前我来见你的理由
you're migrating across to using Realm from MongoDB.
你正要迁移到 MongoDB 开发的 Realm 数据库
Tell us about that process. Why did you start that? How did it go?
请聊聊这个过程   为什么你要迁移   你是怎么迁移的
How long did it take? And what's been the benefits of doing that for you?
这耗时多久   迁移的好处是什么
Yep. So I'll just mention that, uh, this is going onto the clients side of things now.
那么   这又是客户端方面的东西了
So we, we've been using .NET, .NET framework originally,
*Stable 版本。
我们最初用的是 .NET Framework*
and in 2017, I basically decided it was time to rewrite the game.
2017 年   我决定是时候重写游戏了
and to go for completely open sources part of that.
并且把这部分完全开源
Um, it's always been one of my goals to keep as transparent as possible,
尽可能保持透明一直是我的一个目标
so switching to open source was like a no brainer at this point.
那会儿   我想都没想就决定要开源
So we switched to .NET Core,
于是我切换到 .NET Core
um, we were using SQLite,
在早期   我们用的是 SQLite
along with, um, Entity Framework Core in the early days,
搭配 Entity Framework Core
and that worked quite well, but we were using it in a very haphazard way,
有效是有效   但我们使用它的方式非常混乱
because Entity Framework was kind of made more for websites,
因为 Entity Framework 更多是为网站而打造的
where everything is has a very same threading model.
其中所有内容都是一个线程模型
You've got a request coming in and...
你接到一个请求
you're doing various things across that request.
在该请求中执行各种操作
And that's the lifetime over a request.
这个请求就算完了
with a game. That's not the case.
对游戏来讲却不是这样
It's running for, you know, potentially hours on end,
它是要连着运行好几个小时的
and we have all these threads doing different things accessing the same data.
所有这些线程在做不同的事情   却访问相同的数据
So, EF while it worked for us, it was a very haphazard set up.
因此   虽然 EF 管用   但是它用起来非常混乱
and as we tried to migrate from EF2 to EF3,
当我们尝试从 EF2 迁移到 EF3 时
we just hit all these issues where they had enforced all these new rules with threading,
在线程上有了新规则   于是我们遇到了所有这类问题
and we couldn't make it work for us.
这样   EF 就用不了了
So I wanted to fix out threading model,
我们想修好线程模式
our data access model, and Realm had this um.
以及数据访问模式   Realm 就能做到
It was really enticing to me. It has asset compliance,
*Realm 文档和 GitHub Issue 都没有关于 "Assets Compliance" 的说法。本人没有 .NET 或 Realm 开发经验，欢迎大家提出更准确的译法。
它非常诱人   它有资产合规性*
and it really, Realm is very stringent in...
另外   Realm 对你怎样使用线程
how it allows you to do threading, which I saw as a benefit,
非常严格   我认为这是一种好处
even though we would have to put in some initial effort to get that working.
即使我们要投入一些初步努力来让它能用
It meant that we could really streamline,
这意味着我们可以真正精简
streamline our data access and be forced to do things in a in a good way.
简化我们的数据访问   迫使我们用更好的方式写代码
It's quite opinionated, right?
这很顽固   对吧
Yes, definitely.
确实是
Yes, in a good way, though, as you say.
确实   但正如你所说   这是个好办法
Yes.
是的
So you commenced that, I think, probably when we first spoke,
我想   你可能是在我们第一次谈话时开始迁移的
it was towards the end of 2020, the beginning of 2021.
当时正值 2020 年底   2021 年初
And it was completed a while back.
而且前一段时间已经完成了
So, and I would imagine it's not a task you undertook light handedly,
我想这不是一个你轻而易举就能完成的任务
given the scale, you know, this rewrite of the game that you were doing,
鉴于你要做的是整个游戏的重写
Yeah, so, um,
规模相当大
one of the things with osu! is it's a very data driven game,
osu! 的一个特点是   它是一个有大量数据的游戏
because most of the content is user created.
因为大多数内容都是用户创造的
We have basically this huge, local, client side database,
客户端的本地数据库会相当大
and that's one of the main reasons I put so much thought,
这就是我投入如此多心思的原因
and yet wait into the decision to get this right and to switch to Realm.
然后等待做出正确的决定   切换到 Realm
I think I had tried it probably three times over from scratch...
我们从头开始尝试了三次
before I actually figured out how we could make it work.
我们才让 Realm 能用起来
And it was a huge undertaking, but it turned out okay in the end.
这费了好一番功夫   但最终证明一切顺利
Luckily.
挺幸运的
I'm very happy to hear that.
非常高兴能听到这样的话
And I know that the Realm team is, particularly on the .NET SDK team,
而且我知道   Realm 团队   尤其是 .NET SDK 团队
Nikolan and the others, we had some to and forward back conversations.
像 Nikolan 还有其他人   我们和他们进行了前后对话
And indeed, you helped us a lot by things that you discovered.
事实上   你发现的东西帮助了我们很多
Usually, what we find building RSDKs is that we're, I think,
跟大多数开发者一样   通常   我们觉得
like most developers, nearly too close to the bone sometimes to figure out...
在构建 Realm SDK 时   有时我们思考得过深了   过于尖刻了
how this is going to get used in the real world,
以至于无法弄清楚如何在实际场景中使用它
and that it falls and in issues somebody else developing on it might have.
其他人使用 SDK 时   就会出现问题   用不了了
So I very much appreciated the interaction that you had with our development team in that, Dean.
所以我非常感谢你与我们的开发团队在这方面的互动   Dean
And because that helped us a lot. And I think,
你帮了我们大忙
the developers I know in Realm love to hear of it being used out in...
我想 Realm 开发团队听到它能够被实际应用时
the real world and for real.
是很开心的
And that's been very beneficial.
这（对他们）大有裨益
So you're very happy ultimately with how that went.
所以你最终对这一切都很满意
For sure. And, um, yeah, we've got it.
确实   我们做到了
Currently it's pushed out to desktop platforms, so Windows, Linux and macOS.
现在新版游戏已经推向桌面平台   包括 Windows、Linux 和 macOS
and Realm is working great across all those platforms.
Realm 在所有这些平台上都表现出色
We also have it on Android and iOS, but it's kind of in a beta state.
游戏也有了 Android 和 iOS 版   尽管还在测试状态
We're planning on pushing that out further.
我们正计划把它推向更广的群体
But yet, Realm has allowed us to basically push out all these platforms with no issues at all.
而 Realm 使得我们可以毫无问题地把它向所有这些平台上推出
Yeah, it's been a dream to work with.
这是我们的梦想
Even with SQLite, getting the native dependencies right across all these platforms,
虽然只要你把原生依赖配置好   SQLite 也能用
it's kind of on you as a developer,
但你仍然要做好多工作
while Realm kind of has everything kind of in place to make that work.
而 Realm 把所有东西都准备好了   拿来就能用
That's great to hear. I'm going to cut this snippet of the podcast out,
真是太好了   我要把这段播客剪下来
and I'm going to send it on to the engineering team.
发送给开发团队
They would be delighted to hear that first hand feedback.
他们得到一手反馈会很高兴的
You touched on it earlier in so far as osu! in this change...
之前你有说   osu! 的这次改变
that you started in 2017 with the rewrite, you went open source.
自你 2017 年开始重写起   你就把它开源了
Tell us the reasoning behind that.
讲讲这里面的原因吧
So I've always been about transparency in the game...
因为我一直很关心游戏的透明
with how we develop it, and, you know, trying to give back as much to the community,
使开发过程透明   来尽可能地回报玩家社区
but also give back to the development community.
也回报了开发社区
A lot of players are also we have a very,
我们社区中的很多玩家
I guess, a relatively young audience in the community,
我想   都相对年轻
and a lot of the people that are playing the game are also, you know,
许多人在玩这款游戏的同时成长起来
growing up and getting into game development themselves.
并自己加入了游戏开发
So I saw that there was a potential to give back to these players as well,
我认为   我们也有回馈这类玩家的可能
get more involvement, not only on the side of content creation,
让他们参与开发   而不仅仅是内容创作
but having people contribute to the game itself.
是要让人们直接对游戏开发做出贡献
And yet, over the years, like even before we went open source,
这些年里   哪怕是我们还没开源的时候
I had a lot of people ask me if they can help with the game,
就有很多人问我   他们是否能够帮助游戏
and we did bring in quite a few people,
我们也提携了一些人
but there was always this barrier of having a closed source code base,
但始终存在着封闭代码的障碍
where it wasn't very easy to share things upwards.
（闭源时）向上游贡献东西并不容易
Yeah. And, and look, obviously, I mean, that's the main benefit of open source indeed.
是的   很明显   这确实是开源的主要好处
You know, MongoDB origins come from there as well too.
MongoDB 也是源于开源的
How do you manage to...
你是怎么管理这些贡献
handle those contributions and kind of the PRs that you get?
处理各种提拉取请求的呢
You know, I notice from the website, e.g. that it seems that updates are going out weekly.
我去看了你们的网站   新版客户端看起来周更一次
You have a huge change log there. There's lots of people helping out.
更新日志一大堆   许多人都在帮忙
How is that managed from your small team as well too, Dean?
Dean   你的小团队是怎么管理的
Uh. With a lot of stress on the side of some developers,
从开发者角度讲   也是有很多压力的
it's a huge flood of incoming poor requests and issues we get.
我们收到的低质量拉取请求和问题报告太多太多
And this is before we've even gotten live with this open source version.
这还是在我们开始适应这个开源版本之前就有的现象
Like it's still very much in a testing state,
新版仍然处于测试状态
and we've hold back pushing it out to the full user base until now,
到现在为止   我们还没有将其推广到全用户群
because we know that we're just going to get flooded with even more incoming support requests...
因为我们知道   一旦更多用户加入
as we get more users on board.
我们只会被更多的支持请求淹没
So the new version has something in the range of hundreds of...
所以   尽管有成千上万人
thousands of users that have ever opened it.
已经用过新版本
Whereas the actual game is, you know, several magnitudes higher than that.
但实际的游戏群体比这要高好几个数量级
Yet, I can't really say much about how we manage it.
对于我们如何管理它   我真的没有什么经验
Apart from that, it's still an ongoing point of conflict and point of concern...
此外   如何真正跟上开源贡献和讨论
how to actually keep up with this,
以及随之而来的其他一切
this flow of open source contributions and discussions, everything else that comes with it.
仍然是一个持续的关注点和冲突点
I suppose that's one of the things from...
我想   这是你和社区一起走开源道路时
when you go down this route of open source with the community,
难免碰到的一件事情
it's a good complaint, almost.
必然会招致一些抱怨
You know, you have a lot of PRs, you've got a lot of people raising issues,
你有一大堆拉取请求   有一堆人反馈问题
you've got a lot of people helping you out to fix things.
也有不少人帮你修复问题
But there is that management side of it.
那是站在管理层的角度来看是这样的
But from my eyes, from what I've seen, you're doing a superb job.
但在我的角度   在我的眼里   你做的事可太精彩了
And to keep them, you know, keep it alive.
你让这个项目活跃了起来
So, um, that seems kind of a huge amount of work to manage that level of enhancements.
要管理那种水平的提升   需要大量的工作
And I think that's great. So this is Project Lazer, right?
非常棒   这是新版客户端   对吧
Yes, great, yeah.
是的
So, it's been in gestation for a while.
它已经酝酿一段时间了
When will you push it out fully to the wider community?
你什么时候把它完全推向更广的社区
Yeah, I think we, we started on this in something like 2017,
嗯   我们从 2017 年开始开发
and I think we are finally at the point where maybe...
到现在终于要接近完成了
we get this pushed out completely this year, next year.
我们会在今年或明年全面推出它
Everything is pretty much in place.
一切都已基本就绪
But it's more about the user acceptance side of things now,
现在更多的是关乎用户体验
making sure that all the features that people,
要确保大家期待的特性
because we build up a huge amount of features in the games...
因为我们这些年在游戏中新增了大量特性
over the years that people have come to expect to be there.
玩家多年期望的特性应该在 Lazer 上出现
And the way I developed the game originally, it was, you know,
并且   我最初开发游戏的方式是
just about getting the maximum throughput in features,
仅仅是把最多的精力投入在功能上
not worrying about the codes quality too much.
不怎么关心代码质量
These days, we're doing the exact opposite.
现在   我们恰好反过来
We're making sure that the game is maintainable into the future,
我们要确保在未来   游戏是可维护的
even if I was to stop working on it, or, you know, disappear and someone had to take over.
哪怕是我停止开发了   或者我消失了   其他人需要接管
Yeah, trying to keep everything completely documented and...
我尽量完整地把一切写在文档里
in a way that someone would be, like, very excited to take over the project,
要让别人能非常兴奋地接管这个项目
rather than look at this code base and be like, "oh my God, what have I end up with?"
而不是看着这个代码库   然后想   “卧槽   我得到的是啥玩意”
And is there anything currently kind of hampering your growth,
目前是否有什么东西阻碍了 osu! 的成长
or your scale, or you happy with where everything is at the moment?
或者卡住了 osu! 的规模   还是说你对目前的一切都满意
Or is there, you know, something that's kind of a an ongoing frustration,
或者说有没有什么让你一直沮丧的事
be it technical, be it reach of your community?
是技术困难   还是社区交流受挫呢
I don't think so. No. The main, the main concern is,
我倒不这么想   我们主要考虑的是
just getting this new version out to the users,
把新版本做好   推向用户
and, you know, figuring out what needs to be done,
弄清楚需要做什么
what's left to be done to satisfy the vast majority.
还剩什么要做   来使大多数玩家满意
And I guess the hardest thing there is managing the community,
我认为最难的事是管理团队
managing the feedback we get from users in this day and age,
管理我们从这一代玩家那里得到的反馈
where the vocal minority is often very, very vocal about...
在这个时代   少数派的意见尤其大
things that are missing or things that are done wrong,
经常对缺失的东西或做错的事情直言不讳
putting this into perspective, the larger part of the community,
从社区的大部分人的角度来看
which is very happy with how things are.
大多数人对现状很满意
and also just supporting the different hardware that people are running on and,
我们还要支持人们使用的不同硬件
and getting good performance out of, you know, devices.
无论什么设备   都要发挥良好性能
People are potentially playing this game on PCs from the,
玩家可能会在 10 年甚至 15 年前的电脑上
like, ten years ago, 15 years ago, and they expected to run well.
在那里玩 osu!   他们期望 osu! 能很好地运行
So, you know, re-engineering with the latest libraries and stuff,
你知道   用最新的类库和组件重新开发
but also getting that backwards compatibility is a huge.
又要保证向后兼容性   是个很大的挑战
It is tough to manage those multiple platforms.
跨平台的东西很难管理
As you say, you're on Windows and Linux and macOS, and,
正如你所说   客户端有 Windows、Linux 和 macOS 版本
in beta, well, a mobile in iOS and Android, right?
还有 iOS 和 Android 的测试版   是吧
But very much in kind of beta environment for there.
但是还处于初步测试阶段
I think, as you say,
如你所言
there's a saying that the squeaky wheel gets the most oil,
有句谚语叫   会哭的孩子吃奶多
and I think that's what you're trying to get out there with your community.
我觉得这就是你要和社区尽力去跳开的怪圈
There's that people who will always be the most vocal,
总有些人直言不讳   大声批评
but yeah, they could be very much in the minority.
但他们只是极少数人
And as you said, the satisfied users, and again, you can attest to...
然而   对这感到满意的玩家
you know, your hundreds of thousands of users, maybe on...
Lazer 成千上万的用户可以证明这点
and lazer, versus the much more larger group who are very happy and content with it,
那些非常快乐和满足的玩家占大多数
are the ones that you're not necessarily eliciting the feedback from other than...
但你不一定会从这些人那里得到反馈
they're happy to keep playing.
他们只是乐意玩下去   默默支持
Yeah, but the other thing to remember is that,
但另一件要记住的事是
this feedback usually comes from a good place, like these,
（少数人的）这些反馈通常出于好意
these people are very vocal because they care about the game,
他们直言不讳   是因为他们关心游戏
and they care about getting from the game exactly what they and potentially others expect.
对他们自己和别人预期的游戏表现非常上心
So we do definitely trail our hardest to listen to every single piece of feedback,
因此   我们肯定会尽力听取每一个反馈意见
And you know, I try my best to reply every email I get.
我也尽力回复每一封邮件
It's quite a huge time sink for me actually keeping up with the community.
对我来说   保持与社区的联系是一个相当大的时间耗费
But I feel it's important, even if that takes away a bit from development time.
但我觉得这很重要   即使是它占用了一点开发时间
And I suppose, obviously lazer, that's the biggest next step,
我想   Lazer 最重要的下一步显然是
getting it out to the rest of the community.
把它推向其余的玩家群群
Is there an agenda beyond that, Dean?
在这之后还有计划吗   Dean
Is there, once that stone, we're going to do X, Y, or Z?
比如   把它推出去后   我们还有甲乙丙三步走
or even something that you could maybe tell us about, or,
你可以告诉我们吗
or does that get that out and take a long holiday?
亦或是你脱出身来   给自己放个长假
Well it, I mean, I would love to, one of the things I'd really like to do is,
嗯   我特别想做的事之一就是
uh, work on a different project, but, like, you know,
在别的项目上工作
try something new, or potentially work for someone else,
尝试些新东西   甚至为别人工作都有可能
and just, you know, take a step back.
这样从 osu! 的位子上退下来
But I don't think that's gonna happen.
但我不认为这种事会发生
At this rate, we have this huge backlog of features, which,
我们太慢了   我们有大量积压的功能还没完成
currently we're trying to get, you know, feature parody with the old version.
目前   我们正在尝试用旧版本进行功能模仿
But after that, there's so much users' requests that I just don't see an end in sight.
但在那之后   又有太多用户的请求   看不到尽头
It's, it's a bit scary,
有点吓人
Don't see the end, it's a bit scary,
看不到尽头   确实吓人
but it's a challenge that obviously you have...
但这是一个巨大挑战
given your 15 years with this so far,
而且到目前为止   你显然已经为此付出了十五年的时间
Yeah.
是的
given the fact that you've turned something that was a hobby and an interest into a business,
而且鉴于你已经把兴趣爱好变成了日常业务
and actually employed other people to do that, and built this massive global community,
还雇了别人去做这事   建立起巨大的全球社区
I don't think anybody wants you to step away from this, Dean.
我觉得大家都不想你退下来   Dean
and I think they're obviously looking to build more and more and,
显然他们盼望着建起越来越多的东西
and broaden this,
拓展 osu! 的规模
For sure, and like I wouldn't want to wish on anyone else what I do.
确实   我也不想别人做我做的事情
I think it takes like, a certain degree of insanity to do,
可能我是有些变态
to take on this role.
才能一直坐着这个位子吧
But yet, at the same time, one thing I will say is that,
但同时   还有另一点要说明
like, no matter what happens in the future, I'm very happy.
就是无论未来会发生什么   我都乐于接受
I'm very content with everything we've achieved to the day.
我对我们今天所取得的一切非常满意
And I think it's important to, like, take these things day by day,
我认为重要的是   把这些事情一天天做下去
and just being like so many people have enjoyed this game over the last 15 years,
十五年来   这么多人享受我们的游戏
it's like we could destroy everything today,
因此就算我们今天就毁掉一切
and I would still be content with the fact...
我都（不遗憾）   还算满意
we've been given so much enjoyment back over the last decade.
因为我们在过去十多年间给予了人们许多快乐
Yeah, and I have to heap nothing but praise on you for that,
是的   我必须对你的这一做法表示赞赏
from everything that you've talked about.
对你说的这些我都很认可
And obviously that enjoyment is a reward in itself for you having built this.
显然   这种享受本身就是对你创造 osu! 的奖励
And the facts, I in my view, anyway,
无论如何   在我看来
the fact that you haven't tried to overtly grow this beyond its means,
你没有试图特意地超越其手段来发展它
or overtly monetize it or put barriers in the way of play.
或者公然将其货币化   设置游玩障碍
And that by kind of the supporters' tags that you have,
通过支持者标签系统
you're saying, well, look, we do need some revenue here to keep this going,
你传递了一个信号   我们确实需要收钱来维持 osu! 的发展
but we know what we need and we know how to go about it.
但我们自有分寸   取财有道
And I think that there's something incredibly altruistic about that,
我认为这有一些令人难以置信的利他主义
as well as open source, as well as how you manage that.
比如你的开源举动   比如你管理它的方式
So I think you've done a stunning effort,
所以我认为你已经做出了惊人的努力
and I very much look forward to the continued growth of osu! going forward.
我非常期待 osu! 的持续发展
Is there anything else you'd like to share with the podcast audience?
您还有什么想与播客观众分享的吗
And people out there, as I alluded to earlier,
正如我前面提到的
there's a lot of developers out there who would love to take their hobby,
有许多开发者希望把他们的爱好
their interests, into their day job.
他们的兴趣   变成他们的职业
And you obviously have done this. You've walked the walk, talk the talk.
而你显然已经做到了这一点   你有了这样的经验并分享出来
Any advice for those sort of developers that might be teetering on that edge?
对那些可能在这一边缘徘徊的开发者有什么建议吗
Particularly because with COVID, people have been working from home.
尤其是在疫情下   人们在家里工作
They now realize that you don't need an office, forsay, to go to,
他们现在意识到   不需要一个办公室就能上班
You don't need to turn up in a particular place for a particular supplement of time.
你不需要在特定的时间段内出现在特定的地方
So the opportunities, I think, are presenting themselves to developers to,
因此我认为   机会正在向开发者招手
to take on their own projects and side projects,
吸引他们承担自己的项目和副业
and maybe seek and they run with.
他们可能会寻求和运行这些项目
Yeah, I think, um, the way I've always saying it is, all my side projects.
是的   我一直认为
Everything I've worked on has been something that I've...
我所有的副业   所做的一切
both been interested in and something that I've wanted to exert myself.
都是我既感兴趣的东西   也是我自己想要为之努力的东西
Whether that's improving and existing service...
无论是不是改善现有的服务
that doesn't quite do what I want to do.
那种不能完全做我想做的事的服务
I always build for myself and then push it out to the public.
我都是为我自己开发   然后把它公开
And if that catches on, then it does.
如果它流行起来   那么它确实成功
But I'm, I'm not really developing things with, you know, marketing,
但我在开发时   并不考虑营销
or whether it's financially viable in mind.
也不会真的考虑在财务上是否可行
I think that's important thing is to set off just trying to build an amazing product.
我认为最重要的是现在就开始   纯粹地试着制造一个令人惊叹的产品
There's so many examples of that in the past,
在过去   这种例子数不胜数
particularly in the tech space of developers scratching an itch, something they wanted to fix,
特别是科技领域的开发者想要满足自己的需求   想解决的问题
that all of a sudden pivoted and snowballed and grew into something else.
突然间   这个项目滚雪球一样迅速扩大   变成另一种东西
But I think in your case, you know,
但是   在你身上
I'm really impressed with what you've built at osu! and how you've gone about it.
我对你在 osu! 上建立的东西和你建立的方式印象深刻
And this has been a fascinating conversation.
这次谈话真是引人入胜
So for the listeners, before we finish, where again,
结束之前   我想再问一遍
just remind us where we can go to play it,
到哪里可以玩到 osu!
or the GitHub repo, to go and become part of the community and contribute.
它的 GitHub 仓库在哪里   这样大家就可以成为社区一员并贡献了
Ah, yep. So you can go to, osu.ppy.sh to grab the game,
那么   你可以进入 osu.ppy.sh 下载游戏
or you can go to GitHub. @ppy is our organization, and everything's listed there.
或者去 GitHub   我们的账号是 @ppy   所有东西都在那里
Excellent. This has been great.
好的   这次谈话真棒
I do appreciate your time in joining us.
非常感谢你抽出时间来参加我们的会议
And as you said earlier, you don't view this as work.
正如你之前提到的   你并不把它视为工作
I can attest to that, because you're in Japan. I'm in Ireland.
我可以证明这一点   因为你在日本   我在爱尔兰
We've got a nine hour time difference. It's super late your time.
我们之间有九个小时的时差   而且你那边已经很迟了
You're more than happy to jump on this podcast.
你很乐意加入这次播客
And for that, I thank you, Dean.
因此   谢谢你   Dean
So we do appreciate you join in us,
很高兴你能加入我们
and we look forward to following the progress of osu! as it goes forward.
我们期待着关注 osu! 的进展
Yep. Thanks, Shane, what's a great conversation.
好的   谢谢   Shane   这次对话真棒
As you can probably tell, I really enjoyed my conversation with Dean,
你很可能看出来了   我很享受与 Dean 的对话
and it amazes me the level of commitment he has to osu! and to the osu! community.
他对 osu! 和对 osu! 社区的奉献程度让我惊讶
It really stands out that this is more than a job or a business for him,
对他来说   这不仅仅是一份工作或一份业务
and that behind everything there's a sense of purpose, community and vision.
这一切背后都有一种目标感   社区感和远见
I very much look forward to watching the continued success of osu!.
我非常期待看到 osu! 继续成功
If you want to try it out for yourself,
如果你想试玩 osu!
the links to the website and repos mentioned in the show are in the shown notes,
请打开我们提到的网址
so do check those out, also.
请一定要来看看它
Like Dean, if you have a story of interest to our listeners,
另外   如果你像 Dean 一样   也有着吸引我们听众的故事
we're always looking for guests on The MongoDB Podcast,
我们一直在寻找 MongoDB 播客的嘉宾
so if you feel that you can contribute,
所以如果你觉得你可以做贡献
do get in touch with us at podcast@mongodb.com.
请联系我们   地址是 podcast@mongodb.com
And we'd very much love to hear from you.
我们非常希望听到您的故事
Thanks again for listening. We really appreciate it.
感谢倾听   我们不胜感激
If you did enjoy this episode, as ever,
如果你喜欢这集
pleased to leave us a rating and even a review on whatever podcast platform you use.
无论你用哪个播客软件   请打个分或留下评论
It really does help us.
这对我们帮助很大
So for me, Shane McAllister, and the rest of the podcast team,
请务必关注我   Shane McAllister   以及播客团队的其他成员
until next time, do take care, and thanks for listening.
谢谢收听   我们下次再见